## Rudra Dave

Front-end Developer

#### **Connect**

- +91 9328946515
- in rudra-dave-8144302b8
- Rudradave0901
- Ahmedabad India

#### Languages

English

Hindi

Gujarati

#### **Skills**

HTML, CSS, JavaScript.

#### **Frameworks**

Bootstrap, Tailwind, Jquery, React | S

### Tools

Visual Studio Code, Visual Studio, Sublime 3.

### Other

Linux, mongoDB, Git, Github.

#### **Soft Skills**

Communication

Team collaboration

Time management

#### **About Me**

As a Front-end Developer with 2.5+ year of hands-on experience in crafting responsive and engaging web applications and websites. I am excited to join an organization where I can showcase and further develop my skills, contribute to driving business growth, and seize opportunities for career advancement while contributing to the organization's success.

#### Education

### Deepak Highschool Amreli - 365601

2017-2018

10th (SSC) - 63.8%

#### Deepak Highschool Amreli - 365601

2019-2020

12th (HSC) - 57.3%

#### PKM College, BKNMU University - Junagadh

2020-2023

Bachelor's Of Computer Application (BCA) Graduated With CGPA: 8.3/10

### **Work Experience**

## Fronted Developer @ TXlabs (Ahmedabad, Gujarat, India | June 2024 - Present)

- Applied secure coding practices to build web applications and protect against XSS and CSRF attacks.
- ☑ Implemented access control mechanisms to safeguard sensitive user data.
- © Implemented secure coding practices (e.g., input validation) to mitigate XSS and CSRF attacks in web applications.

# Fronted Developer @ Glorywebs- Creatives PVT. LTD (Ahmedabad, Gujarat, India | April 2023 - May 2024)

- Oeveloped responsive and user-friendly websites and web applications using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- © Collaborated with backend teams to develop secure authentication mechanisms using OAuth 2.0 and JWT.
- Oeveloped modules that emphasized web application security basics. and Developed and monitored error logs to detect anomalies that could indicate potential security issues.
- Trained students on secure coding standards and best practices to prevent web vulnerabilities.

# Web development Trainer @ IANT - institute of Advance Network Technology (Junagadh, Gujarat, India | Oct 2022 - March 2023)

- © Conducted comprehensive training sessions on web development technologies, including HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and popular frameworks like React etc
- Oesigned and delivered engaging curriculum and course materials tailored to diverse learner backgrounds and skill levels.

#### **Achievements**

- ⊗ Reduced security issues by 30% through proactive log monitoring.
- ⊘ Improved site responsiveness across devices by implementing TailwindCSS.
- ⊗ Built and deployed 10+ responsive websites and web apps using React, Next.js, and TailwindCSS.
- Improved load speed of a major client website by 45% using front-end performance optimizations.
- ⊘ Integrated PDF and Excel reading libraries to enhance data management features in real-time dashboards.